Rithik Banerjee

.Net Developer

Passionate software developer with around one year of experience in .Net framework, that includes understanding system requirements, designing architecture, development, testing, updating and support of commercial application. Extensive knowledge in object oriented programming, web development, database management and version control.

- banerjee13rithik@gmail.com
- rithikbanerjee.github.io/profile
- twitter.com/banerjee_rithik
- github.com/RithikBanerjee

- (+91) 990 347 1021
- in linkedin.com/in/RithikBanerjee
- S live:banerjee13rithik
- stackoverflow.com/users/13430233

WORK EXPERIENCE

Web Developer

Opticodes Technologies 🗷

07/2019 - Present

Full Time Web Developer responsible for planing architecture, coding, versioning and maintaining a GST based portal.

Kanpur, Uttar Pradesh

- Developed custom modules and components namely, Query Creator, Dapper Method Store, Request Handler, Validation Engine, Auora etc.
- Built a general purpose class library to import data in bulk from excel sheet to database irrespective of its template and header.
- Created GST, E-invoice and E-way bill generating portal using NIC APIS.

Contact: Abhishek Sharma - +91 84008 90312

iOS Developer

TenPi Technologies 🛂

05/2017 - 07/2017 Kolkata, West Bengal Intern iOS Developer responsible for building a iOS app which communicates with nearby bluetooth devices.

- Integrated Bluetooth 4.0 Low Energy API.
- Designed and implemented the back end.
- Responsible for version control of the project.

TECHNICAL SKILLS



PROJECTS

Aleph (04/2020 - 07/2020) 🗹

- Music playing web application based on Django framework.

Excel Data Importer (01/2020 - 03/2020) C

 ORM module to import excel data based on .Net framework.

GSP SDK (11/2019 - 02/2020) [7

- Goods & Services Tax module based on Rest APIs.

Iris Detector (09/2018 - 04/2019) 🗗

Python module used in iris based bio-metric authentication.

EDUCATION

B. Tech in Computer Science

Jalpaiguri Government Engineering College (MAKAUT) 🕝

2015 - 2019 Jalpaiguri, West Bengal

HOBBIES

Article Writing 🛂

Author at C#Corner.

Competitive Coding 🗹

Certified in Problem Solving, Rest API, Python, Java & JS.

Higher Secondary

National Gems Higher Secondary School (CISCE) &

2013 - 2015 Kolkata, West Bengal

LANGUAGES

English

Hindi

Full Professional Proficiency Full Professional Proficiency